<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Werenode Official Website Blog</title>
        <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog</link>
        <description>Werenode Official Website Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>fr</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IOTPAY Test Version]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/IOTPAY Test Version</link>
            <guid>IOTPAY Test Version</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We are excited to introduce the test version of the IOTPay application, designed to transform the landscape of automated IoT payments. This release marks a significant step towards seamless, secure, and efficient transactions within the Internet of Things (IoT) ecosystem.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to introduce the <strong>test version</strong> of the IOTPay application, designed to transform the landscape of automated IoT payments. This release marks a significant step towards seamless, secure, and efficient transactions within the Internet of Things (IoT) ecosystem.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="key-features">Key Features<a class="hash-link" href="#key-features" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><ul><li><p><strong>Automated IoT Payments</strong>: IOTPay enables devices to autonomously process payments, eliminating the need for manual intervention and enhancing operational efficiency.</p></li><li><p><strong>Secure Transactions</strong>: Leveraging advanced security protocols, IOTPay ensures that all transactions are protected against potential threats, maintaining the integrity and confidentiality of your data.</p></li><li><p><strong>Real-Time Monitoring</strong>: Stay informed with instant updates on transaction statuses and device activities, allowing for proactive management and swift issue resolution.</p></li><li><p><strong>Scalability</strong>: Designed to support a growing network of IoT devices, IOTPay scales effortlessly to accommodate your expanding business needs.</p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="benefits-to-users">Benefits to Users<a class="hash-link" href="#benefits-to-users" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><ul><li><p><strong>Enhanced Efficiency</strong>: By automating payment processes, IOTPay reduces operational delays and minimizes human errors, leading to smoother workflows.</p></li><li><p><strong>Improved Security</strong>: Our robust security measures protect against unauthorized access and data breaches, ensuring peace of mind for your business and customers.</p></li><li><p><strong>Comprehensive Oversight</strong>: With real-time monitoring and detailed analytics, you gain valuable insights into your IoT payment operations, facilitating informed decision-making.</p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="about-iotpay">About IOTPay<a class="hash-link" href="#about-iotpay" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p>IOTPay is committed to delivering innovative payment solutions tailored to the evolving IoT landscape. Our mission is to empower businesses with tools that drive automation, security, and efficiency in payment processing.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="participate-in-the-test-phase">Participate in the Test Phase<a class="hash-link" href="#participate-in-the-test-phase" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p>We invite businesses and developers to participate in this test phase to experience firsthand the capabilities of IOTPay and contribute to its refinement. Your feedback is invaluable in shaping a solution that meets the diverse needs of the IoT community.</p><p><a href="https://iotpay.werenode.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IOTPAY web application</a></p><p><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1-JWTfjeJG5ymB0Gcm6YfhZrTJekcClTlujCdKkRZ3Os" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">And give us your feedback!</a></p><p><em>Note: This is a test version of the IOTPay application. Features and functionalities are subject to change based on user feedback and ongoing development.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>IoT</category>
            <category>payment</category>
            <category>NGI</category>
            <category>Web3.0</category>
            <category>BWRC</category>
            <category>werecoin</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Werenode Best Web3.0 Company in France]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/WerenodeOnTop</link>
            <guid>WerenodeOnTop</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Werenode Crowned as the Number One Web3.0 Company in France in December 2024]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Werenode Crowned as the Number One Web3.0 Company in France in December 2024</strong></p><div align="center"><a href="https://www.f6s.com/werenode/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/f6sawarddark.png" width="500" height="auto" class="img_ev3q"></a></div><p>In a significant milestone for the blockchain and electric vehicle (EV) charging industries, Werenode has been officially recognized as the number one Web3.0 company in France as of December 2024. This prestigious ranking underscores the company’s pioneering efforts in integrating blockchain technology with sustainable mobility solutions, reinforcing its status as an industry leader in the evolving decentralized ecosystem.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="revolutionizing-ev-charging-with-web30"><strong>Revolutionizing EV Charging with Web3.0</strong><a class="hash-link" href="#revolutionizing-ev-charging-with-web30" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h3><p>Werenode’s groundbreaking approach leverages blockchain and decentralized finance (DeFi) principles to democratize and streamline electric vehicle charging. By utilizing token-based access and transparent smart contracts, Werenode has effectively disrupted traditional charging networks, fostering an open, user-driven ecosystem where private individuals and businesses can share charging infrastructure efficiently.</p><p>The company’s unique model enables EV station owners to tokenize their charging services, allowing for seamless peer-to-peer transactions. This innovation eliminates intermediaries, reduces costs, and enhances the accessibility of charging points, paving the way for a more efficient and sustainable future in electric mobility.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="a-year-of-monumental-achievements"><strong>A Year of Monumental Achievements</strong><a class="hash-link" href="#a-year-of-monumental-achievements" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h3><p>2024 has been a defining year for Werenode, marked by major technological advancements, strategic partnerships, and recognition within the Web3.0 space. Some of the key highlights include:</p><ul><li><strong>Expansion of Werenode’s Charging Network</strong>: Werenode significantly increased its global footprint, bringing more charging stations onto its decentralized platform and expanding partnerships with major industry players.</li><li><strong>Advancements in Smart Charging and Sustainability</strong>: The company integrated AI-driven smart charging mechanisms, optimizing energy consumption and enhancing grid stability.</li><li><strong>Participation in High-Profile Web3.0 Initiatives</strong>: Werenode actively contributed to European blockchain research projects, further cementing its reputation as a thought leader in decentralized infrastructure.</li><li><strong>Successful Fundraising and Community Growth</strong>: With increasing investor confidence and community engagement, Werenode secured substantial funding to accelerate its mission of decentralized energy sharing.</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="why-werenode-stands-out-in-the-web30-space"><strong>Why Werenode Stands Out in the Web3.0 Space</strong><a class="hash-link" href="#why-werenode-stands-out-in-the-web30-space" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h3><p>Unlike traditional charging networks, Werenode’s Web3.0-powered platform ensures full transparency, trust, and security through the use of smart contracts and decentralized identity solutions. This allows EV users to access stations without cumbersome registration processes or third-party interventions, significantly improving user experience and accessibility.</p><p>Additionally, Werenode’s integration with Decentralized Energy Communities (DECO) aligns with global sustainability goals by promoting energy sharing and optimizing renewable energy usage in EV charging.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="looking-ahead-the-future-of-werenode"><strong>Looking Ahead: The Future of Werenode</strong><a class="hash-link" href="#looking-ahead-the-future-of-werenode" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h3><p>Following this remarkable recognition as the leading Web3.0 company in France, Werenode is poised to drive further innovation in the space. The company aims to:</p><ul><li>Expand its decentralized charging network across new regions, enabling more users to benefit from tokenized access to EV stations.</li><li>Strengthen its role in blockchain governance and regulatory dialogues to promote the adoption of decentralized mobility solutions.</li><li>Continue refining its AI-driven smart charging technology to improve energy efficiency and cost-effectiveness for users.</li><li>Foster community-driven initiatives that empower individuals to actively participate in the future of sustainable mobility.</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="a-landmark-moment-for-web30-and-ev-mobility"><strong>A Landmark Moment for Web3.0 and EV Mobility</strong><a class="hash-link" href="#a-landmark-moment-for-web30-and-ev-mobility" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h3><p>Werenode’s distinction as the number one Web3.0 company in France is a testament to its relentless pursuit of innovation, sustainability, and decentralization. As the world increasingly shifts towards smart and eco-friendly solutions, Werenode’s blockchain-powered EV charging ecosystem serves as a beacon of progress in the Web3.0 revolution.</p><p>With its transformative impact on electric mobility and its steadfast commitment to an open and decentralized future, Werenode continues to lead the charge in Web3.0 innovation, setting new standards for the industry and inspiring the next generation of blockchain-driven enterprises.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Web3.0</category>
            <category>F6S</category>
            <category>IoT</category>
            <category>blockchain</category>
            <category>innovation</category>
            <category>start-up</category>
            <category>FrenchTech</category>
            <category>payment</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IOTPAY]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/IOTPAY</link>
            <guid>IOTPAY</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In our interconnected world, the Internet of Things (IoT) is becoming increasingly integral, permeating sectors from smart homes to complex industrial systems. The proliferation of IoT devices has led to an exponential increase in data generation, with estimates suggesting that IoT devices contribute significantly to the 160 zettabytes (ZB) of data produced globally. This surge underscores the critical need for efficient, secure, and autonomous payment systems tailored for IoT ecosystems.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="project-description">Project Description<a class="hash-link" href="#project-description" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p>Traditional payment infrastructures are often ill-suited for the autonomous and decentralized nature of IoT devices. The necessity for human intervention, coupled with transaction fees and security vulnerabilities, hampers the seamless operation of IoT networks. To address these challenges, Werenode has developed IOTPAY - a decentralized autonomous payment system designed specifically for IoT devices.</p><p>IOTPAY is a research initiative by Werenode, developed within the NGI Sargasso framework-an EU-funded program dedicated to fostering a human-centered, trustworthy, and sustainable internet. The project focuses on creating a decentralized public key infrastructure tailored for IoT devices, utilizing blockchain-driven smart contracts to enable secure, traceable, and feeless data sharing across connected devices. By eliminating intermediaries, IOTPAY facilitates direct transactions between IoT devices, enhancing efficiency and reducing costs. Its blockchain foundation ensures enhanced security and transparency, making it a robust solution for the evolving IoT landscape.</p><div align="center"><a href="https://werenode.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/logo_IOTPAY.png" width="200" height="auto" class="img_ev3q"></a></div><p>IOTPAY was developed within the <strong>NGI Sargasso</strong> framework, Open Call #3. NGI Sargasso is an EU funded project which has Grant Agreement Number 101092887.</p><div align="center"><a href="https://ngisargasso.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/Sargasso.png" width="150" height="auto" class="img_ev3q"></a></div><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="key-features">Key Features<a class="hash-link" href="#key-features" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p>1) Decentralized Autonomous Payments: Eliminates intermediaries, allowing direct transactions between IoT devices.
2) Feeless Transactions: Reduces costs associated with traditional payment systems.
3) Enhanced Security: Utilizes blockchain technology to ensure secure and traceable transactions.
4) Reduced Operational Costs: Streamlines processes, minimizing administrative overhead.
5) Improved Traceability: Provides transparent transaction histories for auditing and compliance.
6) Easy Scalability: Designed to accommodate growing IoT networks seamlessly.
7) Real-Time Efficiency: Facilitates instant transactions, improving system responsiveness.</p><p>Leveraging blockchain technology, IOTPAY ensures that each transaction is secure, transparent, and traceable, thereby enhancing trust within the network. This decentralized approach not only streamlines processes but also significantly reduces administrative overhead, leading to more efficient operations.</p><p>Designed with scalability in mind, IOTPAY seamlessly accommodates the rapid expansion of IoT networks, ensuring consistent performance regardless of network size. Its architecture supports real-time transactions, which enhances system responsiveness and allows for immediate data exchange and decision-making. By reducing transaction fees, IOTPAY makes microtransactions economically viable, opening up new possibilities for IoT applications that require frequent, low-value exchanges.</p><p>The enhanced traceability provided by IOTPAY offers transparent transaction histories, facilitating auditing and compliance with regulatory standards. This feature is particularly beneficial in sectors where data integrity and accountability are paramount. By integrating these capabilities, IOTPAY not only improves operational efficiency but also fosters a more secure and reliable IoT environment, paving the way for innovative applications and services in the rapidly evolving digital landscape.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="potential-applications">Potential Applications<a class="hash-link" href="#potential-applications" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p>IOTPAY offers versatile applications across various sectors by enabling secure, autonomous transactions between Internet of Things (IoT) devices. By leveraging IOTPAY's capabilities, these sectors can achieve greater efficiency, security, and automation in their operations.</p><ul><li><p>Energy Management for Smart Buildings: IOTPAY enables secure, value-driven energy transactions between IoT devices within a decentralized energy community, optimizing energy consumption and promoting sustainability.</p></li><li><p>Automatic Payment of Fees for Logistics: Streamlines logistics management by automating payments for processes involving fees or digital documentation, enhancing efficiency and reducing manual intervention.</p></li><li><p>Connected Cars: Facilitates autonomous payments for services such as tolls, parking, and charging, enhancing the convenience and efficiency of transportation systems.</p></li><li><p>Remote Healthcare: Supports secure transactions between medical IoT devices, ensuring timely payments for services and data sharing, thereby improving patient care.</p></li><li><p>Cognitive Cities: Enables seamless transactions between interconnected devices in smart cities, supporting services like public transportation and infrastructure management.</p></li><li><p>Smart Homes: Automates payments for smart home services and devices, enhancing user experience and operational efficiency.</p></li><li><p>Supply Chain Management: Facilitates secure and autonomous payments within the supply chain, improving transparency and reducing delays.</p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="architecture--protocol">Architecture &amp; Protocol<a class="hash-link" href="#architecture--protocol" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p>The architecture of IOTPAY comprises several core components:</p><p>1) Public Blockchain Network: Serves as the foundational layer, ensuring transparency and security.
2) Smart Contracts: Automate the issuance and revocation of certificates, manage data sharing processes, and enforce conditions without the need for intermediaries.
3) Embedded Wallet: Integrated into IoT devices, it manages digital currency and tokens, facilitating seamless transactions.
4) User Interface: A web application for IoT service providers to manage certificates, monitor transactions, and oversee device interactions.
5) Mobile Application: Offers key administrative features for on-the-go management of IoT devices and services.</p><p>A simplified overview of IOTPAY protocol is showed below:</p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/IOTPAY_protocol1.png" class="img_ev3q"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/IOTPAY_protocol2.png" class="img_ev3q"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a class="hash-link" href="#conclusion" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p>IOTPAY represents a significant advancement in the realm of IoT, addressing the critical need for autonomous, secure, and efficient payment systems. By leveraging blockchain technology and smart contracts, it eliminates intermediaries, reduces costs, and enhances the overall efficiency of IoT ecosystems. As the IoT landscape continues to expand, solutions like IOTPAY will play a pivotal role in shaping the future of interconnected devices and services. Indeed, the market is poised for significant growth. Market assessments project a Total Addressable Market (TAM) of $350 billion by 2030, with a Serviceable Obtainable Market (SOM) of $16 billion. This growth is driven by the increasing adoption of IoT devices and the need for efficient and secure autonomous payment solutions. IOTPAY's innovative approach positions it as a key player in this evolving IoT landscape, offering solutions that align with the increasing demand.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>IoT</category>
            <category>blockchain</category>
            <category>smart contracts</category>
            <category>decentralized identifiers (DID)</category>
            <category>verification certificates (VC)</category>
            <category>payment</category>
            <category>device management</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DID-IMP Project]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/DID-IMP</link>
            <guid>DID-IMP</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Today the Internet of Things, or IoT, is increasingly a part of everyday life, from smart homes to complex industrial systems. Almost half of the 160 ZBs (zettabytes) currently produced in the world are generated by IoT devices. Although it is difficult to determine the exact market size due to different segments and applications, several market research companies have estimated the size of the Big Data market.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are proud to announce the <strong>test release</strong> of the <strong>DID-IMP</strong> application — a decentralized identity infrastructure designed to securely manage and automate data exchange across Internet of Things (IoT) ecosystems.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="-what-is-did-imp">🔐 What is DID-IMP?<a class="hash-link" href="#-what-is-did-imp" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p><strong>DID-IMP</strong> (Decentralized Public Key Infrastructure for Defended IoT Data Management and Procurement) provides a secure and scalable framework for managing digital identities of connected devices. It uses <strong>decentralized identifiers (DIDs)</strong>, <strong>verifiable credentials (VCs)</strong>, and <strong>smart contracts</strong> to ensure trust, traceability, and automation in device-to-device interactions.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="️-key-capabilities">⚙️ Key Capabilities<a class="hash-link" href="#️-key-capabilities" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><ul><li><strong>Automated, Fee-less Data Exchange</strong>: Devices can authenticate and exchange data without central coordination — using smart contracts deployed on the Alastria blockchain.</li><li><strong>Embedded Wallets for Devices</strong>: Manage signing keys and transaction authorizations directly within connected hardware.</li><li><strong>Modular Software Architecture</strong>: Includes reusable components for DID &amp; VC management, service registries, and device-level delegation.</li><li><strong>Web and Mobile dApp Interface</strong>: Built with Angular, our web application enables easy interaction with DIDs, credentials, and history.</li><li><strong>Seamless Integration</strong>: Ready to interface with a broad range of IoT protocols and infrastructures — from smart buildings to industrial fleets.</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="-why-a-test-version">🎯 Why a Test Version?<a class="hash-link" href="#-why-a-test-version" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p>This release is part of our validation process under the TrustChain NGI initiative. We invite developers, IoT operators, and cybersecurity experts to test the system, evaluate its performance, and provide feedback.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="-try-it-out">📥 Try It Out<a class="hash-link" href="#-try-it-out" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p><a href="https://did-imp.werenode.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DID-IMP web application</a></p><p>Developers can access the source code and test interfaces here:</p><ul><li>Dashboard UI: <a href="https://github.com/NGI-TRUSTCHAIN/DID-IMP" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">github.com/NGI-TRUSTCHAIN/DID-IMP</a></li><li>Smart Contracts and deployment tools are included and documented.</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="-whats-next">💡 What’s Next?<a class="hash-link" href="#-whats-next" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p>The DID-IMP test version lays the foundation for a future of decentralized, verifiable, and secure IoT systems. Your feedback will help us improve UI/UX, integration workflows, and security resilience.</p><p><em>Be part of shaping the future of decentralized identity. Join the test phase, build with us, and let’s make data trustless — yet trusted.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>IoT</category>
            <category>blockchain</category>
            <category>smart contracts</category>
            <category>decentralized identifiers (DID)</category>
            <category>verification certificates (VC)</category>
            <category>data security</category>
            <category>device management</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Our latest Twitter-X publications]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/Twitter Feed article</link>
            <guid>Twitter Feed article</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Here are our latest posts on Twitter:]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here are our latest posts on Twitter:</p><div><a class="twitter-timeline" data-theme="light" data-tweet-limit="5" href="https://twitter.com/werenode">Tweets by @<!-- -->werenode</a></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>ev</category>
            <category>twitter</category>
            <category>x</category>
            <category>bitcoin</category>
            <category>werecoin</category>
            <category>tezos</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DID-IMP Project]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/DID-IMP</link>
            <guid>DID-IMP</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We are proud to announce the test release of the DID-IMP application — a decentralized identity infrastructure designed to securely manage and automate data exchange across Internet of Things (IoT) ecosystems.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are proud to announce the <strong>test release</strong> of the <strong>DID-IMP</strong> application — a decentralized identity infrastructure designed to securely manage and automate data exchange across Internet of Things (IoT) ecosystems.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="-what-is-did-imp">🔐 What is DID-IMP?<a class="hash-link" href="#-what-is-did-imp" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p><strong>DID-IMP</strong> (Decentralized Public Key Infrastructure for Defended IoT Data Management and Procurement) provides a secure and scalable framework for managing digital identities of connected devices. It uses <strong>decentralized identifiers (DIDs)</strong>, <strong>verifiable credentials (VCs)</strong>, and <strong>smart contracts</strong> to ensure trust, traceability, and automation in device-to-device interactions.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="️-key-capabilities">⚙️ Key Capabilities<a class="hash-link" href="#️-key-capabilities" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><ul><li><strong>Automated, Fee-less Data Exchange</strong>: Devices can authenticate and exchange data without central coordination — using smart contracts deployed on the Alastria blockchain.</li><li><strong>Embedded Wallets for Devices</strong>: Manage signing keys and transaction authorizations directly within connected hardware.</li><li><strong>Modular Software Architecture</strong>: Includes reusable components for DID &amp; VC management, service registries, and device-level delegation.</li><li><strong>Web and Mobile dApp Interface</strong>: Built with Angular, our web application enables easy interaction with DIDs, credentials, and history.</li><li><strong>Seamless Integration</strong>: Ready to interface with a broad range of IoT protocols and infrastructures — from smart buildings to industrial fleets.</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="-why-a-test-version">🎯 Why a Test Version?<a class="hash-link" href="#-why-a-test-version" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p>This release is part of our validation process under the TrustChain NGI initiative. We invite developers, IoT operators, and cybersecurity experts to test the system, evaluate its performance, and provide feedback.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="-try-it-out">📥 Try It Out<a class="hash-link" href="#-try-it-out" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p><a href="https://did-imp.werenode.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DID-IMP web application</a></p><p>Developers can access the source code and test interfaces here:</p><ul><li>Dashboard UI: <a href="https://github.com/NGI-TRUSTCHAIN/DID-IMP" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">github.com/NGI-TRUSTCHAIN/DID-IMP</a></li><li>Smart Contracts and deployment tools are included and documented.</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="-whats-next">💡 What’s Next?<a class="hash-link" href="#-whats-next" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h2><p>The DID-IMP test version lays the foundation for a future of decentralized, verifiable, and secure IoT systems. Your feedback will help us improve UI/UX, integration workflows, and security resilience.</p><p><em>Be part of shaping the future of decentralized identity. Join the test phase, build with us, and let’s make data trustless — yet trusted.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>IoT</category>
            <category>blockchain</category>
            <category>smart contracts</category>
            <category>decentralized identifiers (DID)</category>
            <category>verification certificates (VC)</category>
            <category>data security</category>
            <category>device management</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[InvestisseurTV]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/InvestisseurTV</link>
            <guid>InvestisseurTV</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Werenode : le booking des stations de recharges électriques]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="werenode--le-booking-des-stations-de-recharges-électriques">Werenode : le booking des stations de recharges électriques<a class="hash-link" href="#werenode--le-booking-des-stations-de-recharges-électriques" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h3><p>Werenode propose une solution numérique basée sur la technologie Web3.0 pour la recharge des véhicules électriques. Cette solution permet l'installation de bornes connectées à un coût optimisé tout en offrant des services à valeur ajoutée tels que la gestion de groupes d'utilisateurs, la traçabilité, la recharge intelligente (smartcharge), le paiement et le roaming. De plus, Werenode développe une solution décentralisée pour les communautés énergétiques, mettant en avant les synergies entre la production d'électricité individuelle et la gestion intelligente de la recharge des véhicules électriques.​</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="équipe-fondatrice">Équipe Fondatrice<a class="hash-link" href="#équipe-fondatrice" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h3><p>L'entreprise a été fondée par six experts dans les domaines de la mobilité électrique, du Web3 et des solutions de paiement :​</p><ul><li>Benoît Maïsseu (CEO) : Diplômé de CentraleSupélec en 1996, il a été directeur de la stratégie des véhicules électriques pour l'Alliance Renault-Nissan-Mitsubishi.​</li><li>François Chiron (CTO) : Ancien élève de l'École Polytechnique (promotion 1992) et de CentraleSupélec (1996), il possède 25 ans d'expérience en informatique, avec une expertise en cybersécurité, intelligence artificielle et internet des objets.​</li><li>Nadiya Khokhryakova (Présidente) : Titulaire d'un PhD de l'Université Paris I La Sorbonne, elle est une entrepreneuse en série ayant lancé sa propre ligne de vêtements en 2001 en Ukraine et conseille de nombreuses start-ups.​</li><li>François Colet : Diplômé de l'ENSPG en 1991, il est un expert mondial de la recharge pour véhicules électriques et l'un des principaux auteurs de la norme ISO15118.​</li><li>Benoît Rognier : Titulaire d'un MSc en informatique de l'Université de Nottingham, il est co-fondateur et conseiller, ancien CTO de Probance et co-fondateur d'Edukera.​</li><li>Gaëtan Cadéro : Diplômé de CentraleSupélec (1996) et titulaire d'un MBA de HEC, il a dirigé le programme de réduction des émissions de CO2 chez Lafarge et a occupé des postes de direction chez Lafarge-Holcim, Chronopost France et OVH Cloud.​</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="positionnement-et-modèle-économique">Positionnement et Modèle Économique<a class="hash-link" href="#positionnement-et-modèle-économique" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h3><p>Werenode se positionne comme un opérateur de mobilité avec sa propre application et un accès aux plateformes d'interopérabilité comme GIREVE, permettant de commander une session de recharge sur potentiellement 450 000 bornes en Europe. L'entreprise bénéficie de coûts opérationnels réduits grâce à sa maîtrise des technologies Web3.0 et offre une solution économique aux entreprises tout en conservant des fonctionnalités clés telles que la traçabilité des recharges et la gestion de groupes d'utilisateurs.​
Le modèle économique repose sur des commissions perçues sur les sessions de charge gérées par l'application, avec une commission maximale de 9%, ainsi que sur des revenus récurrents liés à la gestion des bornes de charge.​</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="performances-et-levée-de-fonds">Performances et Levée de Fonds<a class="hash-link" href="#performances-et-levée-de-fonds" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h3><p>En 2023, Werenode a réalisé un chiffre d'affaires de 100 000 €, démontrant une traction intéressante en B2B. L'entreprise cherche à lever 400 000 € pour accélérer son développement commercial, avec une valorisation pré-money de 1,9 million d'euros, consolidée par le cabinet d'experts Estimeo-Linkera. Cette levée de fonds a débuté par une campagne de crowdfunding via la plateforme Kriptown.​</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="distinctions-et-appel-aux-investisseurs">Distinctions et Appel aux Investisseurs<a class="hash-link" href="#distinctions-et-appel-aux-investisseurs" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h3><p>Werenode a été reconnue pour son expertise en Web3.0, recevant plusieurs distinctions, notamment le prix B-HUB comme meilleur projet Blockchain européen en 2021, et a remporté les projets européens Ontochain (2023) et Trustchain (2024). L'entreprise est également lauréate de Paris &amp; Co - Quartiers Urbains d'Innovation 2023 et a récemment obtenu le Grand Prix Innovation Plastic Omnium 2023.​
L'équipe exceptionnelle de Werenode, composée d'experts aux compétences complémentaires, invite les investisseurs à profiter de cette opportunité de participer à la croissance de l'entreprise, qui est à un point d'inflexion de son activité.​</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="lentrevue">L'entrevue<a class="hash-link" href="#lentrevue" title="Lien direct vers {heading}">​</a></h3><p><a href="https://www.investisseur.tv/video/werenode-le-booking-des-stations-de-recharges-electriques" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" alt="Werenode : le booking des stations de recharges électriques" src="/fr/assets/images/InvestisseurTV-d345f33ee70e41b56d3e03986b4259e2.png" width="1201" height="672" class="img_ev3q"></a></p><hr>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>EVcharging</category>
            <category>Web3.0</category>
            <category>booking</category>
            <category>investment</category>
            <category>payment</category>
            <category>device management</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Smart Charging Concept]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/Smart Charging article</link>
            <guid>Smart Charging article</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Smart charging for electric vehicles (EVs) is the use of cutting-edge technology to streamline the charging of EVs. Utilizing the electric grid more effectively, enhancing vehicle performance, and lowering costs for EV owners are all achievable with this technology.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Smart charging for electric vehicles (EVs) is the use of cutting-edge technology to streamline the charging of EVs. Utilizing the electric grid more effectively, enhancing vehicle performance, and lowering costs for EV owners are all achievable with this technology.</p><p>The ability to shift charge time to during off-peak hours, when electricity demand is low, is a major benefit of EV smart charging. This can save EV owners a lot of money while reducing the burden on the electric grid. Renewable energy sources, like solar and wind power, can be embodied into the charging process with the effectiveness of smart charging technology.</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://werenode.com/img/iso3D_ecosystem_charge.jpg" class="img_ev3q"><p>Additionally, smart EV charging has the potential to significantly contribute to lowering greenhouse gas emissions and enhancing air quality. The need for electricity to power EVs will rise as more of them are utilized. In order to lessen the overall environmental impact of EVs, smart charging technology can help to ensure that this electricity is produced from clean, renewable sources.</p><p>With the impressive advantages this technology provides, it could provide even more if merged with the power of Blockchain technology as we all know the applaudable impact bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies has had in the world economy these past years.</p><p>In order to enable advanced grid management, smart charging technology can also be integrated with other smart grid technologies like energy storage, demand response, and distributed energy resources. Utility companies and grid operators will be able to manage the incorporation of renewable energy sources more effectively and optimize the use of the electric grid as a result.</p><p>In conclusion, smart charging for Electric Vehicles is a crucial technology that can help to streamline the charging of EVs, lower costs for EV owners, enhance vehicle performance, and lessen the overall environmental impact of EVs. The use of EV smart charging technology is anticipated to increase in the future as EV adoption rises and efforts are made to create a cleaner, more sustainable transportation system.</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://werenode.com/img/Werenode_concept.jpg" class="img_ev3q"><p>Werenode is a Company that develops software solutions to provide services for the charging of electric vehicles. Using its mastery of blockchain technologies among others, Werenode created a solution that can incorporate the features of several modern services associated with electric vehicle charging and blockchain, including services like: Plug &amp; Charge, Vehicle to Grid and the Technology of the day “Smart charging”. Werenode also provides several payment options for users which includes Fiat and Crypto payment (This allows for a secure, traceable and scalable transaction among others).
Find some more info about <a href="https://coinpaprika.com/coin/bwrc-werecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Werecoin</a> and <a href="https://coinpaprika.com/coin/btc-bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bitcoin</a> on <a href="https://coinpaprika.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Coinpaprika</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>ev</category>
            <category>smart-charging</category>
            <category>crypto</category>
            <category>bitcoin</category>
            <category>werecoin</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zycrypto article about Werecoin]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/Zycrypto article</link>
            <guid>Zycrypto article</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A new article on Zycrypto covers Werenode's offering of Werecoins.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new <a href="https://zycrypto.com/werenode-has-launched-the-ico-of-wrc-token-on-14th-february-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">article</a> on Zycrypto covers Werenode's offering of Werecoins.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>ev</category>
            <category>ev-charging</category>
            <category>werecoin</category>
            <category>tezos</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Werecoin Offering listed on ICOholder]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/ICOholder listing</link>
            <guid>ICOholder listing</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Werecoin Offering is listed on ICOholder.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://icoholder.com/en/werenode-1015060/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Werecoin Offering</a> is listed on ICOholder.]]></content:encoded>
            <category>listing</category>
            <category>werecoin</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Werenode recognized as best startup 2021]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/B-Hub Winner 2021</link>
            <guid>B-Hub Winner 2021</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Werenode has been marked as the top Startup in 2021 by the European B-Hub project More on B-hub]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Werenode has been marked as the top Startup in 2021 by the European B-Hub project <a href="https://b-hub.eu/blockchain-startups-france/#werenode" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">More on B-hub</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>article</category>
            <category>werecoin</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Werenode's MVP is live]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/MVPlive</link>
            <guid>MVPlive</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Werenode's MVP is live, featuring the first blockchain framework allowing to create and manage the electric vehicles charging infrastructure and to pay an EV charge with a dedicated token: Werecoin.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Werenode's MVP is live, featuring the first blockchain framework allowing to create and manage the electric vehicles charging infrastructure and to pay an EV charge with a dedicated token: Werecoin.</p><iframe width="100%" height="416px" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/z9FOELbbDi0" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"></iframe>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>MVP</category>
            <category>video</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reddit topic about Tezos and Werenode]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/Reddit Tezos Werenode topic</link>
            <guid>Reddit Tezos Werenode topic</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A new reddit topic about Tezos and its first real time-real life application Werenode.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new reddit topic about Tezos and its first real time-real life application <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/tezos/comments/l3o4cr/werenode/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Werenode</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>reddit</category>
            <category>tezos</category>
            <category>werenode</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Financing innovation]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/defiinnovation</link>
            <guid>defiinnovation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Werenode is releasing its draft white paper describing its blockchain financing innovation. This technical document establishes the main principles of a decentralized investment system using Tezos blockchain native mechanisms like baking. This includes the new Continuous Delegation Offering concept combined with a Continuous Security Reward. Additionally, a Decentralized Autonomous Organization is used to overview the token governance.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Werenode is releasing its draft <a href="/fr/docs/defiwhitepapers">white paper</a> describing its blockchain financing innovation. This technical document establishes the main principles of a decentralized investment system using Tezos blockchain native mechanisms like baking. This includes the new Continuous Delegation Offering concept combined with a Continuous Security Reward. Additionally, a Decentralized Autonomous Organization is used to overview the token governance.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>whitepaper</category>
            <category>tezos</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Werenode's smart contracts go mainnet]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/gomainnet</link>
            <guid>gomainnet</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Werenode is proud to announce that its smart contracts are now entering Tezos' main net. Eager at spurring the development of the EV charging infrastructure, whether public or private, we have designed with our partner Edukera a set of Tezos smart contracts which allows to build an open framework for safe and auditable EV charging payment.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Werenode is proud to announce that its smart contracts are now entering Tezos' main net. Eager at spurring the development of the EV charging infrastructure, whether public or private, we have designed with our partner Edukera a set of Tezos smart contracts which allows to build an open framework for safe and auditable EV charging payment.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>mainnet</category>
            <category>tezos</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet Werenode's POC]]></title>
            <link>https://werenode.github.io/fr/blog/meetpoc</link>
            <guid>meetpoc</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Werenode's first POC, featuring a blockchain framework built on Tezos smart contracts, allowing to create and manage new EVSE easily and to pay an EV charge with a dedicated cryptocurrency is ready. This will also simplify the implementation of ISO15118 thanks to distributed certificates.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Werenode's first POC, featuring a blockchain framework built on Tezos smart contracts, allowing to create and manage new EVSE easily and to pay an EV charge with a dedicated cryptocurrency is ready. This will also simplify the implementation of ISO15118 thanks to distributed certificates.</p><iframe width="100%" height="416px" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bqemw8UWK3Q" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"></iframe>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>POC</category>
            <category>video</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>